見ていたんでしょう
戦死
ブリッジ直撃コース
地球人は皆敵だ
スカイキャリアのデータによると
確証は無い　偶然かもしれない
あなたのスカイキャリアがアルギュレを運んだんだ
でも　今はこれしか手掛かりが無い
上空の敵機　急降下　側面からも三機接近
地球の劣等民族が　タダで済むと思うなよ
マグバレッジは私が引き取られた里親の名です
その機体が乗った船は　南南西に進路を取っていた
そして　トリルラン卿が敗北した時
いえ　殺されたんですよ　あなたに
ブラド卿を倒したカタフラクトは　オレンジ色の機体だったんですね
その通りだ　オレンジ色の小賢しい奴に…
アセイラム姫は　地球のオレンジ色の機体と一緒に居た
種子島での戦闘　私の兄も参加していたんです
地球機に敗北した軌道騎士は　ブラド卿とトリルラン卿の二人のみ
旧姓はヒュームレイ　あなたの親友は私の兄です
You inferior Terran!
Don't think you'll get away with this!
命中　ラスト
An orange Cataphract killed Sir Vlad, right?
Every last Terran is the enemy!
駄目
Your sky carrier transported the Argyre.
You saw it unfold.
You're right.
弾切れ
艦長
That sneaky orange gutter-wretch killed him.
終わりだ
Only two Orbital Knights have been defeated by Earth forces: Sir Vlad and Sir Trillram.
And when Sir Trillram was defeated,
Princess Asseylum was with the orange Cataphract.
何事
あれ　生きてる
According to the sky carrier's data, that unit was on a ship headed south-southwest.
あれは…
I can't be sure.
It might be a coincidence.
But this is the only lead I have.
My older brother participated in the battle at Tanegashima as well.
君が見る夢は　古いインクで紙に書いた祈りのよう
He fell in battle.
Or rather, he was killed.
小さなその手が　縋るものも　今はまだ何処にも無い
By you.
Magbaredge is my adoptive family's name.
それでも君の行く道を
My birth name was Humeray.
奇麗なものは奇麗なままで　守り続けたいと思うよ
Your best friend was my brother.
The unit above us is nosediving!
Three others closing in on our flanks!
They're headed straight for the bridge!
空と水が星を染めて
淡く虹を描いて散って
Direct hit!
Last one!
眩しい夜　君が歌う
Oh no...
声は何処まで届くのだろう
I'm out?
Captain.
憧れの住まう蒼い星のひかり
This is the end.
ただ僕らは恋をして
What was that?
たったひとつの未来の為に
Huh?
We're alive?
今の全て奏でてみる
飛び立つよ　まだ暗い空へ
That's...
That bastard...
おのれ　どこまで私を愚弄する気だ
How long will he continue to make a fool of me?
タルシスで出る　スカイキャリアの用意を
I will go out in the Tharsis.
Prepare a sky carrier.
待たれよ　クルーテオ卿
Pray wait, Count Cruhteo.
ザーツバルム卿　何故止める
Why do you delay me, Count Saazbaum?
生け捕りを所望したのでは無いのか
Did you not ask that I capture him alive?
追撃に気付いて　行き先を変えられては困る
If he finds himself pursued,
he may change his destination.
あの者がどこへ行くつもりか知りたい
I would like to determine
where he intends to go.
どういう事だ
What do you mean?
貴公は何故あの者が謁見の間を使ったと思われる
Why do you believe he made use of the audience chamber?
もしスパイであれば　仲間が居るであろう
If he indeed is a spy, surely he has accomplices.
案ずるな　我が上から追跡しよう
Worry not.
I will track him from above.
敵の増援？
Enemy reinforcements?
しかし　攻撃を止めてくれました
No, it shot down their attack.
仲間割れ？
Infighting?
Who knows?
さあ　獲物を取り合いしてるだけかも
Maybe they're just fighting over the spoils.
どっちでもいいよ
Fine with me.
敵の敵なら　味方でなくても役に立つ
The enemy of my enemy may not be my friend,
but he can still be useful.
邪魔立てをするはどこの家紋の者か
Which clan does this interloper belong to?
この地は既にフェミーアンが取った
This island is Femieanne territory!
妾の領地で　勝手は許さぬ
It belongs to me.
I won't tolerate your willful behavior!
行け　我が眷属達よ
Fly, my children!
ボティスの指が…
Botis' fingers...
おのれ
You'll pay for this!
鞠戸大尉　鞠戸大尉　大丈夫ですか
Lieutenant Marito!
Are you okay?
ヒュームレイ
Humeray!
掴まれ　ヒュームレイ
Grab my arm, Humeray!
鞠戸
Marito...
Humeray!
ヒュームレイ　今助ける　ヒュームレイ
I'll get you out of there, Humeray!
全然当たんない
I can't hit them!
距離を取った　という事は…
They're distancing themselves.
Which means...
Control!
コントロール　ウェルドックを開けてください
Open the well dock!
マスタング22っす
It's Mustang 22!
艦長
Captain!
Kaizuka's little brother?
界塚弟か　いいでしょう
Do it.
耳を塞いで
Cover your ears!
皆さん　耳を塞いでください
Everyone! Cover your ears!
ママ
Mommy!
何
Look!
A hidden dock?
隠しドック
機関は
Engine status!
生きています
Working order!
船体は
Hull?
ぎりぎり　いや　浸水が
Barely holding.
No, we're taking on water.
前方のドックに突っ込め
Make a beeline for that dock!
ぜ…前進いっぱい
A-All ahead!
What?
ちょ　伊奈帆
Inaho!
マスタング11　私達も行くわよ
Mustang 11 here!
We're going in too!
なお君　どういうつもり　勝手に
What's this about, Nao?
Don't run off like that!
ユキ姉こそ　船の護衛は
And what about you, Yuki?
Shouldn't you be defending the ship?
あんたね
You little...
機銃掃射　目標　ゲート上部の岩盤
Fire a Gatling gun.
Target the bedrock above the gate.
しかし…
But ma'am—
Fire!
撃て
皆
Guys...
What's that orange guy planning?
何をするつもりだ　あのオレンジ色
Now, then...
さて　あの三面六臂をやっつけよう
Let's take care of that Asura.
The Landing Castle will soon reach an airspace
from which we can scan the Japanese archipelago.
まもなく当揚陸城は　日本列島のスキャン可能空域に入ります
Once we're in range, focus on finding
the sky carrier stolen by Slaine Troyard.
探知エリアに入り次第
スレイン·トロイヤードが奪取したスカイキャリアを捜索せよ
アセイラム姫は　生きています
Princess Asseylum...
is alive.
僕はこの目で見ました
I saw her with my own eyes.
ザーツバルム様
Count Saazbaum.
当該機　発見しました
Carrier located.
It is above Tanegashima, in the southwest of the Japanese archipelago,
日本列島南西部　種子島上空
and appears to be engaging
Femieanne's Cataphract, Hellas.
現在　フェミーアン伯爵のカタフラクト　へラスと交戦中の模様
What?
何
Tanegashima, you say?
種子島だと
What is this place?
ここは一体…
I've never heard of a base of this magnitude on Tanegashima.
種子島にこのような基地があるとは聞いていませんが
とにかく　退艦を急ぎましょう
But first, let us focus on evacuating the ship.
Lieutenant!
大尉
大丈夫ですか　鞠戸大尉
You okay?
Lieutenant Marito!
No pushing!
押さないで　煙を吸い込まないように
Don't breathe in the smoke!
急いで
非戦闘員の避難を最優先　続いて負傷兵だ
Your top priority is to evacuate the civilians.
Followed by the wounded.
No one gets left behind.
一人も残すな
はい
Yes, sir!
Matsuribi!
祭陽先輩　マスタング小隊は？
Where's Mustang Platoon?
韻子達が甲板に居ないんです
Inko and the others aren't on the deck!
まだ戦ってますよ　外で
They're still fighting out there.
They're using themselves as decoys so we can escape.
俺ら逃がす為に　囮になってんよ
そんな…
No way!
命中　次　右に3ミル
Direct hit.
Next one is 3 mil right.
了解
Roger.
Those things will have to break through bedrock to get at the assault ship.
強襲艦を襲うには　岩盤を砕かなければいけない
To increase their impact,
they have to increase their speed.
威力を上げるには　速度を上げる必要がある
ロケットの加速には　必ず距離が必要だ
And accelerating a rocket always requires distance.
距離が長いと　少し角度がずれただけで　狙いは大きく外れる
But at great distances, even a tiny change in its bearing will cause it to miss greatly.
Enemy at 4 o'clock!
四時の方向に敵　こっちに向かってくる
It's heading this way!
問題無い
Not a problem.
火星の攻撃機が守ってくれる
The Martian craft's attacks will keep us safe.
おのれ
Damn you!
もう　何がどうなってるの
Jeez!
What the hell is going on?
Yuki, let's put the pressure on the enemy Cat.
ユキ姉　敵のカットを直接攻めよう
What?
Are you crazy?
何言ってるの　あんなのに敵うわけないじゃない
We'll be swatted like flies!
どうかな　意外にこけおどしかも
Are you sure?
It might be weaker than it looks.
韻子　ハンドガン借りるよ
Inko, let me borrow your handgun.
O-Okay.
第11　12ブロック　退避確認
Evacuation of blocks 11 and 12 confirmed.
第8ブロックの退避も　完了しました
Block 8 has also finished evacuating.
これで全員ですね
That's everyone, then?
はい　我々も急ぎましょう
Yes, ma'am.
We should get going too.
Any contact with Mustang Platoon?
マスタング小隊と連絡は
いえ
Not yet.
無事を祈るしかありませんね
All we can do is pray for their safety, then.
マグバレッジ艦長
Captain Magbaredge!
不見咲君　避難民の先導は
Mizusaki? What happened to leading the refugees?
全員を　先の貨物室に一時退避させました
They're resting in a cargo room further ahead for now.
But...
実は　艦長に見ていただきたい物が
there's something you need to see.
姫様
Your Highness...
私のせいなのですか
Is it my fault?
私が　地球に来たからなのですか
Did this happen because I came to Earth?
Your Highness!
姫様
私が来なければ　暗殺は起きなかった
If I hadn't come, there would have been no assassination.
そうすれば　この戦争も　人々が不条理に苛まれる事も
And with no assassination, there'd be no war.
Nobody would have had to suffer unjustly.
そうよ
That's right.
覚えておいて　この人達にとって　火星人は皆敵だから
And you better remember that to them,
Martians are the enemy.
What's the meaning of this?
一体どういう事だ
I wish I knew, ma'am.
見当も付きません
For what purpose was this facility built?
何のための施設だここは
Y-Your Highness!
ひ…姫様
Where are you going?
どちらへ
That's...
これは　火星の　カタフラクト
a Martian Cataphract.
一体…
How did it...
This is a crater.
クレーターだ
It wasn't just a single meteor that hit this place.
ここに落ちた隕石は一つじゃない
一つは岸を削って入江を作った
One hit the shore and formed the bay.
そしてもう一つが　ここだ
The other one hit here.
では　この機体は
Then this unit...
Yeah. It's the demon from fifteen years ago.
ああ　15年前の悪夢さ
I'd always assumed Heaven's Fall had wiped it from existence.
ヘブンズ·フォールの被害で消滅したとばかり思ってたぜ
Talk about a touching reunion.
感動のご対面ってわけだ
鹵獲していたというのですか
So we took it for ourselves?
じゃあ　この事実を隠すために
Are you saying that Lieutenant Marito's Tanegashima Report was buried
鞠戸大尉の「種子島レポート」は闇に葬られたって事ですか
so they could keep this thing a secret?
Moreover...
しかし…　それだけでしょうか
Is this all they were keeping secret?
Captain Magbaredge!
マグバレッジ艦長　あれを…
Look at that!
何ですか…　これは
What on Earth...
is that?
Orange...
オレンジ色
Hey, Nao!
ちょっと　なお君
The Asura hasn't moved for a while.
さっきから三面六臂は　あの場所から動いていない
同じ攻撃を繰り返すだけだ
It just keeps repeating the same attacks.
きっと　あいつの武器はあれだけなんだ
Those fists must be its only weapons.
あとは…
Now...
Cover fire, please.
援護をお願い
えっ　ちょ　なお君
Hey!
Nao!
Inaho!
伊奈帆
No way.
嘘でしょ
Direct channel open.
接触回線オープン
Let's be quick.
手短に行こう　そちらの兵装は
Your armaments?
Around twenty howitzer rounds left. You?
榴弾砲の残りは20発ほど　そちらは
HE弾9発　それで最後だ
Nine HE rounds. Then I'm out.
Nao, stop it! He's a Martian—
なお君やめて　それは火星の…
Sorry, Yuki. We'll talk later.
ごめんユキ姉　あとで
The Hellas' fists can transform into singular macromolecules, upping their defense.
ヘ…ヘラスの拳は　巨大分子となって硬度を増します
どんな弾でも破壊できません
Bullets won't scratch them.
You're wrong.
いや　破壊された拳がある
There was one fist that got destroyed.
I suspect their molecular structure returns to normal when the fingers move.
たぶん　指が動く時は分子構造が戻るんだ
Patch me into the signal from your stabilizers.
スタビライザーの信号を回して
We use different systems!
規格が違いますよ
構わない　解析する
That's fine. I can figure it out.
You've got incoming, Bat.
来るぞ　コウモリ
Bat?
コウモ…
Knew it.
やっぱり
Marax!
モラクス
おのれ
How dare you!
Him and his crazy stunts.
相変わらず無茶なんだから
前進するわよ
Let's press forward.
Are you sure?
いいんですか
いいのよ　あの子の無茶って　大体正解だから
Yeah. Those crazy stunts seem to get results.
Pull them together!
引き付けて
もう一機　真後ろに付けてくれ
One left.
Get right behind it.
装甲のない真後ろからなら　エンジンもいける
Their tails have no armor, which means their engines are also vulnerable.
後方よりさらに二機
Two more incoming from the aft!
Route 1-7-5.
進路175　海岸線に沿って飛んで
Hug the coast.
ユキ姉　聞こえる
Yuki, do you copy?
Oh, now you need our help, huh?
都合の良い時だけ頼るんだから
進路そのまま
Hold your course steady!
ボティス　モラクス
Botis.
Marax.
Ronové.
ロノウェ　ハルファス
Halphas.
ラウム　ヴィネ
Räum.
Viné.
妾の子らを…　よくも…
Those were my children!
We'll attack simultaneously.
同時に仕掛けるわよ
了解
Roger.
You leave me no choice!
ならば奥の手
It's rocketing up.
飛んでった
くそっ
Damn!
What is that?
何だあれは
I don't know either!
僕も知りません
It's gained distance...
距離を取った　加速して来るぞ
It's accelerating this way!
狙撃で軌道を逸らしてください
Shoot it with your rifle and knock it off course!
あのサイズ　ライフルじゃ無理だ
That thing's too big for a rifle!
Well, you're making me too heavy to dodge!
あなたを乗せていると重いんです　避けられません
Prepare to be crushed.
叩き潰してやる
It's coming, Bat!
来るぞ　コウモリ
Quiet, Orange!
黙っていてください　オレンジ色
He dodged?
避けただと
He stalled the engine to quickly lose altitude?
失速させ　落としたのか
It's back.
また来た
I can't pull out!
引き起こしが…
同じ手は食わぬぞ
The same trick won't work twice!
終わりだ
You're finished.
What in the world?
何事
What?
何
これは
That's...
A flying boat?
飛行艇？いや
No.
戦艦か
A battleship?
There you are!
見つけた
アセイラム姫
Princess Asseylum!
Impossible!
馬鹿な
The Terrans have no Aldnoah! How is that thing moving?
アルドノアを持たぬ地球人が　何故その様な物を…
Enemy craft closing in, 12 o'clock!
12時の方向より敵飛行兵器接近　衝突コース
It's on a collision course!
Wretched Terrans!
地球人が
All hands, brace for impact!
衝撃に備えてください
Damn you!
おのれ　まだ…
I'm not finished—
火星人は皆　お父様の仇
All Martians...
will pay for my father's death!
やったね
We did it.
Princess Asseylum!
アセイラム姫　やっと見つけた
I've found you at last!
姫は死んだ
Your princess died.
なのに　何故探している
So...
Why did you seek her out?
Huh?
You must have known that she was alive.
君は姫が生きているのを知っていた　何故だ
How?
What are you talking about?
どういう意味ですか
Answer the question.
答えろ
姫に会わせてください
Take me to Her Highness.
Answer my question first.
僕の質問が先だ
Do you...
もしかして　姫を利用するつもりですか
mean to use her for your own ends?
Use her?
利用されると　困るのか
What's it to you?
You...
あなたは…
Are you my enemy?
あなたは　僕の敵ですか
You...
君は…
are my enemy.
僕の敵だ
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:つっちー    翻译:mam&低音子    校对:zwx    时间轴:Maize    压制:河蟹
kimetsuke bakari
Pigeon-holing
決めつけばかり　自惚れを着た
kimetsuke bakari
Pigeon-holing
unubore wo kita
Endless hubris
cheap na hokori de oto aragetemo
The rage of my low-born pride serves no purpose
チープなhokoriで　音荒げても
cheap na hokori de oto aragetemo
The rage of my low-born pride serves no purpose
ana ni kakushita
I buried the mirror
棚に隠した　哀れな　恥に濡れた鏡の中
ana ni kakushita
I buried the mirror
aware na haji ni nureta kagami no naka
that shows the shame and misery of my existence
zubon no kizu dake hikerakashite
All I see in it are the holes in my clothes
都合の傷だけひけらかして
tegaru na tsuyosa de kachitoru sube wo
I try to hone myself to be victorious despite my mediocrity,
手軽な強さで勝取るの術を
どれだけ磨いでも気はやつれる
dore dake toidemo ki wa yatsureru
but all it does is wear me out
furatsuita shisou doori da
It's a vision of utter foolishness
ふらついた思想通りだ
furatsuita shisou doori da
It's a vision of utter foolishness
I say, cry
愛-same-CRIER　愛撫-save-LIAR
I say, liar
I say, rise in hell
Eid-聖-Rising HELL
I stand gazing down at death
愛してる　Game世界のDay
Don't say, oh
Don't-生-War　Lie-兵士-War-World
Life is
I think
Eyes-Hate-War
Es ist gute Frage, was ist das?
It's a good question, what is it?
A-Z Looser-Krankheit-Was IS das
Es ist gute Frage, was ist das?
Leben, was ist das?
Life, what is it?
Sie kam, siehst du das?
She came, do you see?
Signal, Siehst du das?
Sie kam, siehst du das?
Leben sie tut weil Haus und der Mann will
She lives because house and man want
Rede, die du nicht weisst
Leben sie tut weil Haus und der Mann will
Aus eigenem Willen
Leben, was ist das?
Life, what is it?
Signal, Siehst du das?
Leben, was ist das?
Sie kam, siehst du das?
She came, do you see?
Leben sie tut also in seinen Augen
So she lives in his eyes
Rede, die du nicht weisst
Leben sie tut also in seinen Augen
Sieh mit deinen Augen